

Odysseas Papadopoulos

Toulouse Métropole, France Tel: +33 7 80 53 88 18

Email: odysseas.papadopoulos.career@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ulyssespapadopoulos

Professional Summary

Seasoned International Business Development, Customer Relations and Key Account Strategy Expert with over 30 years of experience across Europe and the Middle East. Specializes in sustainability, renewable energy, green transport, green building and industry sectors. Demonstrated leadership and contacts in international business, C-Suite and Global Industry Groups and Associations. Established linkedin network.

Professional Experience

Occitanie Réseau Développement Durable

President/Volunteer

2020 - Present | Occitanie, France

- Conduct comprehensive market research in sustainability sectors in the Occitanie Region.
- Engage in key industry events and conferences.
- Expand membership base to over 1500 and share best practices and regulatory updates.

Green Transport & Mobility (Air, Land and Sea), Urban Re-planning, Fleet Solutions - EMEAI

President/Volunteer

2019 - Present | EMEAI

- Established & expanded the Green Transport Network to cover EMEAI region.
- Expanded membership to 3500 key industry professionals and leaders.

Green & Sustainability Business Networks (Middle East)

President/Volunteer

2013 - 2020 | Dubai, UAE and then Occitanie, France

- Built networks with businesses to tackle environmental and sustainability challenges.
- Created membership with online B2B portal comprising over 1000 Eco Providers and Clients.
- Organized monthly B2B events on Renewable Energy, CSR, Transport, Recycling.

Green Emirates Consultants FZC

Managing Director and Partner

2012 - 2019 | Dubai, UAE

- Delivered training and workshops on Environnmental & CSR topics.
- Organized and marketed environmental conferences and exhibitions.
- Provided recruitment and career services for Green Sector Clients.
- Sectors : Solar, Energy, Water, Waste, Green Building, Renovations, CSR.

CITYSPACE LLC

Business Development Manager

1998 – 2012 | Dubai, UAE

- Developed a multinational corporate client base, significantly increasing client base and revenue.
- Expanded business and opened remote offices in Qatar and Bahrain Financial Districts.
- Marketing, communications, Business Development Districts.
- Led business development and strategic partnerships in the Middle East.

Quality & Human Resources Management Representative

- Led the establishment of the ISO 9001 program and HR Program
- Obtained ISO 9001 Quality Management Certification for the entire organisation.
- Led the establishment of the HR system. Staff count increased to 65.

Business Development Executive

1994 - 1998 | Dubai, UAE

- Developed a multinational corporate client base, significantly increasing revenue and headcount
- Business development and strategic partnerships in the Middle East

Education

MBA in International Business

Middlesex University (Dubai / UK) 2012 – 2014

Management Training

University of Leicester (UK) 2002 University of New England (AU) 1994

Skills and Competencies

- New Market Development
- B2B Business Development
- International Trade
- Sales Management
- Green & Sustainable Business Sectors & Practices
- Executive Coaching & Mentoring
- Key Account Management Strategy

Certifications

- ISO 9001 / ISO 14001 / ISO 26000 / ISO 50001 / IATA/UFTAA
- Renewable Energy Mini MBA
- Strategic Planning and Urban Design Foundations Training

Languages

- English: Native or Bilingual

- French: French: Full Professional

- Greek : Native or Bilingual